The Miracle Technique Listen for the actual sounds, not what you think they
are. As you saw in Chapter 1, there's a difference between pure sound and
spelling, regaining long-lost listening skills. The trouble with starting accent
training after you know a great deal of English is that you know a great deal
about English. You have a lot of preconceptions and, unfortunately,
misconceptions about the sound of English. A child can learn any language. Every
sound of every language is within every child. So what happens with adults? People
learn their native language and stop listening for the sounds they never hear.
Then they lose the ability to hear those sounds. Later, when you study a foreign
language, you learn a lot of spelling rules that take you still further away
from the real sound of that language, in this case, English. What we're going to do
here is teach you to hear again. So many times you've heard what a native speaker
said, translated it into your own accent, and repeated it with your accent. Why?
Because you knew how to say it.